Guide to the Mabel Doremus papers, 1950-1966.
Doremus, Mabel papers, 1950-1966.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mabel Doremus papers, 1950-1966.
23-14-973
Mabel Doremus, 1905-
1 cubic ft.
Publications, memos, and reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Primarily publications relating to civil defense, especially for farms, published by various New York State and federal agencies including Cooperative Extension and the United States Department of Agriculture. Also some memos and reports.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Doremus received a B.S. from the University of Nebraska in 1928 and an M.A. in 1937 in home economics from Columbia University. She joined the Department of Food and Nutrition at Cornell University in 1950 as an assistant professor and cooperative extension specialist. She was promoted to the rank of associate professor in 1953 and retired as professor emerita in 1966.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Primarily publications relating to civil defense, especially for farms, published by various New York State and federal agencies including Cooperative Extension and the United States Department of Agriculture. Also some memos and reports.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Doremus, Mabel, 1905-
Subjects:
Agriculture--Defense measures.; Civil defense.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Memos and reports, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell, 1964, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- New York State, 1951-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cooperative Extension, 1951-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- NYS Civil Defense Commission New Digest, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- NYS Radioactivity Bulletins, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- NYS Radioactivity Bulletins, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Rural Civil Defense Office Newsletter, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Government Surplus Food, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Government Surplus Food, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Government Surplus Food, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Government Surplus Food, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Government Surplus Food, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- USDA publications, 1952-1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- USDA publications, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- USDA publications, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Federal Extension Service, 1953-1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- You Can Survive, USDA Federal Extension, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Knowledge for Survival, USDA Federal Extension, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Wake Up and Live, Rural Civil Defense Material, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- U.S. Government Civil Defense publications, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- U.S. Government Civil Defense publications, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- U.S. Government Civil Defense publications, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- U.S. Government Civil Defense publications, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Civil Defense Technical Bulletin, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Civil Defense Training Course for the Food Industry, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- United Nations publications, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Other publications and reprints, 1951-1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Clippings, 1961, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Journals, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Magazines, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)